ir. Frank Boerman

Personal data

NAME: Frank Boerman
DATE OF BIRTH: 23 Maart 1994

Adress: De Linnenbleker Boxtel

Nationality: Dutch

PHONE NUMBER: +31 6 44 11 19 57 E-MAIL: frank@fboerman.nl WEBSITE: https://boerman.dev/



Interests

I have a passion for helping to make sense of societal issues, explaining them to both experts and the public. It is important for me that my work helps build a better world for all of us. My main interest on this is currently the energy transition. My drive is to use my knowledge and skills to think of new solutions and improve existing ones. I love to deep dive into analytical topics, both for looking for improvements as well as helping others improve them.

This passion is the driver for my current work at TenneT, working in the heart of the energy transition on the important topics of helping and improving cross border electricity trade, both in the capacity and the market domain.

I also publish public analyses and visualizations on my blog and social media to help the public at large on these energy transition topics.

SKILLS

In the past years I have developed myself as an internationally known expert of Flowbased Capacity Calculation. I support my colleagues with analysis to further improve and advance the Flowbased process, both within TenneT as well as in an european context. I have a proven track record of published analysis on my blog and linkedin, as well as internal publications.

By doing this I have build up experience in writing and presenting analysis, with specific skill in the european energy system and markets. To make my publications possible I also have experience with gathering and processing large volumes of data, for example running my own public data dashboard at data.boerman.dev.

Through my volunteering work I have experience in working with others, managing organizations and learned to negotiate and find solutions considering opposite options.

I speak and write fluently dutch and english and have multiple years professional experience in doing so.

Personality

How other people describe me: self assertive, go-getter, ambitious, meticulous, open and friendly. I love doing hikes in nature, preferable in mountainous areas, but also like to go on culture city trips. Next to this I like to read books on topics of history and international relations.

In my student time I have danced at student dance association esdv Footloose, mainly salsa and bachata.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2020 MASTER ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Eindhoven University of Technology, Eindhoven

Specialization: Embedded Systems

SEP 2012 -

BACHELOR ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

2017

Eindhoven University of Technology, Eindhoven

SEP 2005 -

HIGHSCHOOL: VWO, NT EN TECHNASIUM

Jul 2012

KnippenbergCollege, Eindhoven

Work Experience

Mar 2021 -Now

Process Specialist Flowbased SOP-TRS TenneT

Process Specialist at the System Operations Transmission Services department of TenneT. I act as an internal data analyst to assist my team members mainly on the topic of Flowbased Capacity Calculation.

August 2022 -Now

Founder and owner of Amun Analytics

My business umbrella for all things related to my side projects, mainly data analysis and visualizations. I also do ad-hoc consulting on various topics under this banner.

Aug 2020 -Feb 2021

Junior Engineer LPN TenneT

Traineeship with Large Projects Nederland (LPN), focus at the disci-

plines of secondary and telecom engineering

Aug 2017 -Now

Founder and owner of Kolibri Solutions

Founded in August 2017, Kolibri Solutions is a software development company that specializes in digital administration and python programming. It is a spinoff of the ELE faculty of the TU/e for creation and maintenance of the BEP Marketplace and Master Marketplace. For more

information: https://kolibrisolutions.nl/

May 2019 -

Graduation project: Coherent De-Dispersion of Radio Pulsar Signals

using Dataflow on FPGA

June 2020

In this project I developed an application for the new dataflow platform StaccatoLab. This platform enables mapping data driven dataflow graphs to FPGA's in a user friendly way for fast performance. The application focuses on processing large ammounts of data in a parallel fashion: parsing astronomy telescope data to search for pulsar stars.

More information can be found on my blog https://boerman.dev/

Nov 2018 -

Internship pilot functional safety PMP

Feb 2019

Created a proof of concept for a pilot of functional safety in a motor

control embedded platform (PMP)

Jul 2018 -Nov 2018

Embedded Software Designer at Prodrive Technologies Worked on the Prodrive Motion Platform (PMP)

Aug 2016 - | Programmer Team Marketplace ELE

Aug 2017

Founded by me with support from the faculty to help with the administration of the influx of new students. Developed and maintained the BEP and Master Marketplace systems. Since August 2017 the company Kolibri Solutions is founded from this.

2015 - IOT Programmer ECO group

2017

After successfully completing my Bachelor End Project at the ECO group of the ELE faculty at $\mathrm{TU/e}$ I stayed on as student assistant to help develop an IOT platform. This included creating management platforms, server administration and programming frontend interfaces.

JAN 2015 - | Interface & Backend Programmer EIT-ICT-RICH

DEC 2015

The EIT-ICT-RICH project was a collaboration between the TU/e, NXP, Swedish Institute of Computer Science and the university of Twente on the area of IOT. I was involved in programming a scheduler for wireless transmissions in an IOT network and creating a visualization for network operators. This visualization showed how the network behaved and gave insights on how to optimize it. My bachelor end thesis was based on parts of this work

2015 - Student Assistent TU/e ELE

Tutor with Computation I en II focusing on computer architecture and C programming

2015 - Interface Programmer at Avular

2016 Avular is een startup company that specializes in building drones. I

Volunteer work and other activities

LONILLIC WO	THE THE OTHER MOTIVITIES
November 2023	Expert energy system for national broadcaster NOS Gave interview to dutch news program "nieuwsuur" as an expert on energy systems to provide commentary on political program of Volt for national elections
May 2021 - December 2021	Co-Chair Candidate Committee Municipal Elections 2022 Elected position to select candidates for the election list for the municipal elections 2022 from Volt Arnhem&Nijmegen
2016 - 2020	ICT committee esdv Footloose Responsible for the website as well as administrative systems such as for dance exams and the entire server infrastructure
2017 - 2020	Facility committee esdv Footloose Responsible for maintaining light and other facilities in the dance hall
2017 - 2020	Archive committee esdv Footloose Founded by me, responsible for gathering and archiving all relevant data of the association
2019	Scala Coordinator Introduction 2019 Representative of the culture umbrella association Scala during the negotiations about the Introduction 2019 as well as internal coordinator between all member associations
2015 - 2017	Board Secretary IEEE Student Branch Eindhoven As secretary I was responsible for all communications within the association as well as organizing activities
2015 - 2016	Treasurer Spolu committee Thor With three fellow committee members we organized a study trip to the Czech Republic